<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>daiyi</title>
    <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/</link>
    
    <atom:link href="/blog/rss2.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    
    <description>thoughts and ideas and essays by daiyi; unrefined brain-to-internet pipe; public journaling</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 01:48:27 GMT</pubDate>
    <generator>http://hexo.io/</generator>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mount Warren with Yelly</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2020/08/09/Mount-Warren-with-Yelly/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2020/08/09/Mount-Warren-with-Yelly/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;ridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi I’m Mica, I am a dog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just me and my BFF &lt;a href=&quot;https://ayeletbitton.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;
        
      
      </description>
      
      <enclosure url="http://daiyi.co/blog/summit.jpg" type="image" />
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="ridge.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Hi I’m Mica, I am a dog.</p><p>Just me and my BFF <a href="https://ayeletbitton.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yelly</a> went together for a Sunday stroll up a peak: Mount Warren, 12,332 ft. Having started up the mountain and turned around 4 years ago because it was so boring, Yelly warned me that it would be a boring day. But if there’s anything a dog is good at, it is finding a way to not be bored.</p><a href="map.png"><p><img src="map.png" alt="how we went up mount warren"><br></a></p><p>When Yelly got into the adventure truck that morning I jumped right into the copilot seat, because I know this machine to be a magical portal to interesting places. We headed towards Tuolumne but stopped before we got there. I have <em>still</em> never been to Yosemite, <a href="https://www.nps.gov/yose/planyourvisit/pets.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">I wonder why no one will bring me</a>?</p><div class="photo-small"><p><img src="car.jpg" alt=""></p></div><p>There were plenty of trees at the start of the hike for squirrels to live in, I kept my nose peeled for juicy rodents. Yelly called me a lot in the beginning, but after a while we relaxed into a routine of me going out to scout and Yelly reliably following my lead.</p><p>We passed through some delicious mountain water streams. Yelly kept splashing me!</p><div class="photo-right-pull"><p><img src="forest.jpg" alt=""></p></div><div class="photo-small"><p><img src="stream.jpg" alt=""></p></div><p>Soon the tall grass came to an end and we entered the talus zone.</p><p><img src="talus-boundary.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Yelly stopped us for breaks occasionally, like humans tend to do. Dogs don’t really take breaks, but I would occasionally keep her company (especially since it meant I would recieve food).</p><div class="photo-small"><p><img src="take-a-break.jpg" alt=""></p></div><p>The talus field seemed to go forever into the distance, perhaps the entire mountain was a pile of talus. The sun was hot, and Yelly offered me a lot of water, even when I wasn’t thirsty. When I didn’t drink, she dumped the water on my back!</p><div class="photo-small"><figure><p><img src="drinking.jpg" alt=""></p><figcaption><p>Do I have to??</p></figcaption></figure></div><p>Finally the talus gully brought us to a delightful detour: snow! <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Watermelon_snow" target="_blank" rel="noopener">watermelon flavoured</a> this time. I love snow, it is the ideal playground to dig and wriggle in with little consequence, although I have basically an infinite pain tolerance anyway.</p><video controls autoplay loop><source src="mica-snow.webm" type="video/webm"></video><p>I would be happy to play in the snow all day, but we had to continue to the summit. I found the register! This is my third <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sierra_Peaks_Section#SPS_List" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SPS</a>. There was a big view of Mono Lake below, and Yosemite which I can look at but not walk on(?)</p><div class="photo-small"><p><img src="summit.jpg" alt=""></p></div><div class="photo-section"><div class="photo-right-pull"><div class="photo-small"><figure><p><img src="summit-selfie.jpg" alt=""></p><figcaption><p>Summit selfie with my BFF Yelly!</p></figcaption></figure></div></div><p>We relaxed at the summit as Yelly ate snacks and video called Leo, and I checked out the solar-paneled weather station that had seen better days.</p><div class="photo-inline"><p><img src="views.jpg" alt=""></p></div></div><p>The clouds rolled in for our descent, and Yelly finally stopped splashing me with water. I ran ahead but checked back occasionally to see that she was still following me. That was a great day!</p><p><img src="descent.jpg" alt=""></p><p><em>Thanks to <a href="https://ayeletbitton.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">yelly</a> for the photos. I’m a dog, I can’t use cameras.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2020/08/09/Mount-Warren-with-Yelly/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>West Ridge of Conness</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2020/08/07/West-Ridge-of-Conness/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2020/08/07/West-Ridge-of-Conness/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;In these weird COVID times, the leadership at my job decided there should be at least one company-wide 3-day weekend per month, and if th
        
      
      </description>
      
      <enclosure url="http://daiyi.co/blog/upper-ridge.jpg" type="image" />
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In these weird COVID times, the leadership at my job decided there should be at least one company-wide 3-day weekend per month, and if the federal holiday calendar didn’t provide, they would manufacture it. In search of a partner for my random Friday off in August, I hit up my teacher-friend still enjoying the remains of summer break.</p><p><img src="start.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Alicia and I both kind of fell off the emotional and physical training wagon when the pandemic hit and aren’t at peak strength, so we picked something more leggy with a focus on having fun. And it was really fun! I’m actually glad I procrastinated on doing this climb until I was OP for the grade (5.6) so we were able to simul/solo it in a timely style rather than laboriously pitching out the entire thing. Highly recommend this strategy and this route, it is a classic for a reason \o/</p><ul><li>Gear: mostly single rack (including offset aliens, alicia’s favs), not enough slings, 40m skinny rope (from a double). We folded the 40 in half and used it as a 20m double for simuling. So light!</li><li>Approach: 4hr, 6am start</li><li>Climb: 3.5hr</li><li>Descent: 2.5hr</li><li>car-to-car: 11hr</li></ul><a href="conness-west-ridge-map.png"><p><img src="conness-west-ridge-map.png" alt="route map for west ridge of conness"><br></a></p><p>When I was looking for approach beta from Saddlebag Lake, both <a href="http://www.supertopo.com/packs/highsierra.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">supertopo</a> and <a href="http://maximuspress.com/shop/proddetail.php?prod=GGA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Croft</a>’s tracks went straight up the east ridge, but my speedy housemate <a href="lfranchi.com">Leo</a> and Alicia had both previously approached by the southern ridge. We went with that. I thought it was a mostly straightforward (no snow this year) with easy terrain, although my baseline for comparison is <a href="/blog/2020/08/02/North-Arete-of-Bear-Creek-Spire/" title="Bear Creek Spire">Bear Creek Spire</a> from the previous week. The funny thing about this approach is that you hike up until you’re NEARLY at the summit, and then go through a notch and drop all the way down to the bottom of the west ridge. We messed that part up and accidentally continued towards the summit. I’ve heard from a bunch of people who are pretty capable at routefinding that this approach tripped them up, and I could see why one of the guidebook’s approach beta includes “go with someone who has done it before”.</p><div class="photo-section">  <div class="photo-right-pull"><p><img src="step-across.jpg" alt=""></p>  </div><p>Once we started climbing I didn’t really take photos because we were on the move constantly! I don’t think photos could capture the really cool exposure and breath-sucking knife’s-edge anyway, you have to go see for yourself :D We simuled the first bit, soloed for a while, then roped up for the last pitch as I got lightheaded from forgetting to snack up. Alicia continually checked in on how I was doing since I was the less experienced of us, she didn’t want to pressure me past my risk tolerance. That’s a good alpine partner!</p></div><p><img src="upper-ridge.jpg" alt="soloing near the top"></p><p>Halfway up the wind kicked in and the clouds condensed in that sudden lurch as it happens in the Sierra, as NOAA’s 10% forecast of afternoon thunderstorms manifested as reality. We felt droplets as we signed the summit register and started down the trail to distance ourselves from the incredibly lightning-vulnerable peak before eating our lunch burritos.</p><div class="photo-small"><p><img src="summit-burrito.jpg" alt="summit burrito"></div></p><p>Of course with my luck this summer, the hail came down and was whipped across my face and neck by the wind. I didn’t bother getting my windshell out (I didn’t bring a rainshell), trotting down the ridge slopes while hiding in my sunshirt hood. The sandy trail smelled like wet pavement. The sun taunted us from the adjacent valley.</p><p><img src="valley.jpg" alt="valley"></p><p>The rest of the hike was on-and-off showers as we descended back into the green valley, and we were back at the car at 17:00 and home before 18:00. Though we’ve been in the same covid circle since march, Alicia had just traveled and was self-quarantining, so we masked up to carpool. The sun was out in Mammoth, Mica licked my toes at the door, and Yelly made a delicious dinner. I felt like the luckiest person ☀️</p><p><em>Edited: 2020-08-10</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2020/08/07/West-Ridge-of-Conness/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Arete of Bear Creek Spire (13,726 ft) c2c</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2020/08/02/North-Arete-of-Bear-Creek-Spire/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2020/08/02/North-Arete-of-Bear-Creek-Spire/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;I was surprised when Marco’s idea for “what do you want to do this weekend” involved more than a 20 minute stroll, and even more so when 
        
      
      </description>
      
      <enclosure url="http://daiyi.co/blog/summit-block.jpg" type="image" />
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was surprised when Marco’s idea for “what do you want to do this weekend” involved more than a 20 minute stroll, and even more so when he agreed to a 4am wakeup after I heard stories of friends epic-ing on this climb after getting off-route. We managed it car-to-car (c2c) in 14+ hours, 5:10 - 19:25. Great granite with improbably friendly climbing, neat ridge traversing, sweeping views, amazing weather, and a sloggy but safe descent made a good Sunday run in the mountains.</p><p>Gear: single rack to 2’, large nuts, a duck, many slings, 60m alpine rope.</p><p><img src="ridge-simul.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Here is a map of our approach. It isn’t a gps track, I drew it with digital marker, so it’s useless trying to follow it to the pixel, but I thought it was pretty straightforward to determine irl. We followed <a href="http://maximuspress.com/shop/proddetail.php?prod=GGA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Croft</a>’s approach of leaving the main trail at Gem Lakes, which seemed easy enough, although I did see <a href="https://www.peakbagger.com/peak.aspx?pid=2669" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Peakbagger</a> tracks that left earlier at Long Lake.</p><div class="photo-small"><figure><p><img src="bear-creek-spire-map.png" alt="bear creek spire approach map"></p><figcaption><p>thanks for being a great map tool <a href="https://caltopo.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">caltopo</a>.</p></figcaption></figure></div><p>We left the house in Mammoth at 4:10, starting off the Mosquito Flat trailhead at the end of Rock Creek at 5:10 as the light came in and made my sleepy mind’s eye feel like I was walking in a claymation.</p><p>Though crampons &amp; ice axe are usually necessary this time of year, last season was a blessed (or cursed, depending on your inclinations) mediocre snow year, so we were treated to a minimalistic alpine experience with less gear and shockingly nonexistance mosquitos (spoken as the person who is always first to be bitten). You can see the climb from close to the trailhead, so if in doubt take a look with your eyes (maybe the day before if you’re getting a pre-dawn start), or better yet, get a friend peakbagging in the area to snap a photo for you (thanks <a href="https://ayeletbitton.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yelly</a>!)</p><figure><p><img src="bear-creek-spire-from-long-lake.jpg" alt="bear creek spire from long lake"></p><figcaption>View of the approach and route from the north end of Long Lake. Which is, admittedly, 2 miles from the trailhead.</figcaption></figure><p>After crossing the river downstream of Gem Lakes you would be led to believe by <a href="http://maximuspress.com/shop/proddetail.php?prod=GGA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Croft</a>’s approach map that you must bypass a “Restoration Area: Use Existing Trail” sign and proceed to stomp on sensitive wetland,</p><div class="photo-small"><figure><p><img src="restoration-sign.jpg" alt="restoration sign, keep walking"></p><figcaption>oops</figcaption></figure></div><p>but if you walk a couple hundred feet further there’s now a luxurious and guilt-free developed trail that leads right and up to the biggest Gem Lake before dissolving into a talus slope.</p><p>As we ascended into the talus, we realised it is the friendly kind you can do a confident jog over.</p><figure><p><img src="talus-over-gem-lakes.jpg" alt="coming up from gem lake"></p><figcaption>Gem Lakes (and Chickenfoot lake to the right) in the valley behind us</figcaption></figure><p>We made our way up to Dade Lake as the morning brightened in earnest, although neither of us snapped a photo because we were concerned with refilling water, dropped our packs, and hiking on at top speed. The alpine lake was clear and quiet, its shores dotted with the bright tents of campers just waking up. Meanwhile, I was so hungry that I ate my lunch tamale, even though it was still 8am.</p><div class="photo-small"><figure><p><img src="tamale.jpg" alt="tamale"></p><figcaption>always be feastin'</figcaption></figure></div><p>The last .3 miles were the worst, I am usually a decently paced hiker but I got hit in the face with altitude symptoms (despite having been fine when I was at 12k+ recently) and tried to find my way up the increasingly rotten and steep talus while looking through a straw with ears ringing. We were at the base and climbing around 9:30.</p><p><img src="bear-creek-spire-irl-notes.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Luckily the altitude felt better once I started climbing, while Marco continued to be completely unaffected because his body is a flawless machine. As I was fumbling around with sunscreen on the second pitch, he short-fixed himself and continued running up the rock in a mission to pass the one other party on the route.</p><p>We simuled the 3rd and 4th pitches (class 4) with a duck in the middle.</p><p>In the summer the route gets full sun, though a nice breeze kept it pleasant enough for sun shirts. We did encounter some shade at the top of the 5.8 (5th) pitch (which neither of us did as a chimney…?) which convinced Marco to put on his puffy.</p><figure><p><img src="5.8-pitch.jpg" alt=""></p><figcaption>coming up the 5.8 pitch</figcaption></figure><p>Marco climbed so fast that I had few opportunities to eat bars because my hands were constantly belaying! After that was more easy 5th to the ridge then summit, including a neat tunnel-through:</p><p><img src="tunnel-through.jpg" alt=""></p><p>The party we had passed earlier decided to solo to the summit, while I wanted to continue simuling, so they passed us here. From here we went up and along the ridge, dropping to the right when it got steep then up again.</p><p>We summitted around 2pm. (4.5 hours of climbing)</p><p><img src="summit-block.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Marco got signal and texted our housemates! From a bundle of slings, I did a 30m rap on another party’s rope (marco tossed it then downclimbed) and then we split a lunch burrito. There was a short traverse then sandy class 2 slog down the back side of the ridge.</p><figure><p><img src="abandoned-egg.jpg" alt="abandoned egg"></p><figcaption>a mysterious abandoned (??) egg found on the descent.</figcaption></figure><p>The trick to the descent is to not go through the lowest notch, keep hiking up and poke your head over the ridge occasionally until you see a class 3 route that veers north and down until you hit the approach trail again.</p><p>From there the decent was uneventful. Marco filled up water in the stream feeding Dade Lake, and we boulder-hopped back to Gem Lakes. We passed an older couple setting up camp, enthusiastically asking us how the climb went as they were going to attempt it the next day. I hope I smile that big when thinking about climbing when I’m their age.</p><figure><p><img src="descending-to-gem-lakes.jpg" alt="gem lakes again"></p><figcaption>going back down to gem lakes</figcaption></figure><p>We rejoined the trail at a spooky Sunday twilight hour when it was completely devoid of the usual tourist cluster–it was as quiet as when we had approached at butt oclock this morning, though my fears that we had wandered into a barren alternate sandbox universe was debunked when we got closer to the trailhead and overtook some fishers (who asked if they could catch a lift in our backpacks).</p><p>We caught up with Vanna at the trailhead at 19:25 and were home before dark! Cathie pulled up on the driveway to deliver her wedding invitation right as I was stumbling out of the van, and then we made mac and cheese while falling asleep, just in time for work the next day.</p><p>After that entire day I’m still wondering where the eponymous “Bear Creek” is. Let me know if you find it. \o/</p><p><em>Edited: 2020-08-06</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2020/08/02/North-Arete-of-Bear-Creek-Spire/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hail on Red Slate Mountain</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2020/07/19/Red-Slate-Mountain/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2020/07/19/Red-Slate-Mountain/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;Red Slate Mountain is a 20 mile hike with 5700ft gain from McGee Creek Trailhead, mostly on scenic trail, with the last mile a straightfo
        
      
      </description>
      
      <enclosure url="http://daiyi.co/blog/summit-powernap.jpg" type="image" />
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Red Slate Mountain is a 20 mile hike with 5700ft gain from McGee Creek Trailhead, mostly on scenic trail, with the last mile a straightforward class 1-2 scree ridge. It took us 10.5 hours. That’s a pretty good day, for a dog.</p><p><img src="caltopo-map.png" alt=""></p><p>We pulled up to the trailhead at 5:20am, with the morning light already arriving. The first couple of miles are pretty gentle, an unnotable sandy path.</p><div class="photo-small"><figure><p><img src="morning-trailhead.jpg" alt=""></p><figcaption>My butt with the Sierra ridges catching morning light as we begin.</figcaption></figure></div><p>We encountered a log bridge river crossing, which I confidently traversed without any help, to the surprise of the human pack.</p><p><img src="logjam-crossing.gif" alt=""></p><p>I was so excited to be playing with my friend Piton and his cousin Kami visiting from the city! They’re small but fast.</p><p><img src="mica-and-piton.jpg" alt=""></p><p>We leaped through meadows, terrorizing alpine chipmunks and sipping in streams. The skyline was dominated by contrasting creamy granite slabs, and red-streaked volcanic scree.</p><p><img src="meadow2.jpg" alt=""></p><div class="photo-small"><p><img src="meadow.jpg" alt=""></p></div><p>I got so hot from running that I sat in a river crossing to cool off.</p><div class="photo-small"><p><img src="stream-soak.jpg" alt=""></div></p><div class="photo-section">  <div class="photo-right-pull"><p><img src="little-mcgee-lake.jpg" alt=""></p>  </div><p>After passing a billion interesting lakes left and right, the human pack made their first and last stop at Little McGee to fill up their water bags. We scrambled down the talus to the water, and daiyi picked me up and dunked me in the chilly alpine lake!! Supposedly it’s because they knew it would be my last opportunity to cool off before the ascent to the pass and then the peak. I rolled on my back in the dirt to regain dignity and dryness.</p></div><div class="photo-section">  <div class="photo-left-pull photo-small"><p><img src="dogs-selfie.jpg" alt=""></p>  </div><p>The daschunds turned around here as the trail became a scree pile, so I said goodbye to Piton and his humans.</p></div><p>The terrain took a shift from soft dirt to red scree switchbacks until McGee Pass. I gazed into the next valley over, mentally calculating how many alpine chipmunks must be in there.</p><p><img src="mcgee-pass.png" alt=""></p><p>Suddenly, a new friend joins the party as we head for the summit. He walked really quickly to catch us, which is impressive for a human, although I am definitely faster.</p><figure><p><img src="red-slate-scree.jpg" alt=""></p><figcaption>In my natural environment, where I am shockingly camouflaged.</figcaption></figure><p>I encounter a surprise: snow! (Somehow the humans completely ignored this fun detour to roll around, prance, and dig).</p><div class="photo-small"><p><img src="ridge-snow.jpg" alt=""></div></p><p>We arrive at the summit in time for lunch. Daiyi inhales a summit burrito without even sharing.</p><div class="photo-small"><p><img src="summit-burrito.jpg" alt=""></div></p><figure><p>We had passed a couple backpackers heading down, but had the summit to ourselves.</p><p><img src="calling-leo.jpg" alt=""></p><figcaption>I watch in amusement as Yelly video calls Leo from the summit, classic.</figcaption></figure><p>As the clouds roll in, I become a donut and take a powernap.</p><div class="photo-small"><p><img src="summit-powernap.jpg" alt=""></div></p><p>The breeze picks up, so the humans start down the mountain with the afternoon t-storm forecast in mind.</p><p>Here’s Little McGee on the way up, and then how it looked on the way back, ominous clouds and silver water:</p><div class="photos"><div class="photo"><p><img src="looking-back-on-little-mcgee.jpg" alt=""></p></div><div class="photo"><p><img src="back-to-little-mcgee.jpg" alt=""></p></div></div><p>By the time we hit the lake, I felt the first drop of water, and when we reached treeline we heard thunder! The hail started falling so fast that it hurt and we hid behind a tree for a couple minutes before the humans started to trailrun (which was my strategy all along).</p><p>After a couple of miles, we outran the rain.</p><p><img src="mica-shake.gif" alt=""></p><p>The final miles were longer and flatter than I remember. I even ceded my customary position at the head of the pack and heeled behind daiyi. We finally got back to the truck around 4pm. I was a tired dingo and became a donut on the asphalt as the humans did their post-hike stretches and drank their protein juices.</p><p>Back home, Leo made dinner for everyone (I had kibble and peanut butter).  I passed my bean check, no bloody toes even with all the scree, just a couple of hot spots, which makes sense considering my 10.5 hours of continuous trotting.</p><p>My second <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sierra_Peaks_Section#SPS_List" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SPS</a> peak completed, I collapsed into power-saving mode for the next 2 days, behaving like a normal dog for once.</p><p><img src="slepy-dingo.jpg" alt=""></p><p><em>Thanks to <a href="https://mountains.ayeletbitton.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">yelly</a>, <a href="https://www.peakbagger.com/climber/Climber.aspx?cid=18362" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rafee</a>, <a href="https://daiyi.co">daiyi</a>, and sadie for the photos ✨</em></p><p><em>Edited: 2020-07-22</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2020/07/19/Red-Slate-Mountain/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Joaquin Mountain: My first SPS</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2020/07/09/San-Joaquin-Mountain-My-first-SPS/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2020/07/09/San-Joaquin-Mountain-My-first-SPS/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No pudeo escribir mi blog, porque soy una perra. Mi CTO daiyi traduce la historia de mi primera aventura de &lt;a href=&quot;https:/
        
      
      </description>
      
      <enclosure url="http://daiyi.co/blog/summit-friends.jpg" type="image" />
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>No pudeo escribir mi blog, porque soy una perra. Mi CTO daiyi traduce la historia de mi primera aventura de <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peak_bagging" target="_blank" rel="noopener">peak bagging</a>.<br>– Mica</p></blockquote><p>✨</p><p>The summit of San Joaquin Mountain is situated so you can see both the dramatic granite of the Sierra valleys and hanging glacial lakes to the west, and also the volcanic red and white sand slopes to the east. The first 2.5 miles were on a OHV dirt road through a forest (also a popular mountain biking route), and the use trail after that is simple to follow because you just stay on the ridgeline the entire time. Easy for dogs like me.</p><p><a href="https://caltopo.com/map.html#ll=37.68623,-119.08888&amp;z=14&amp;b=f16a&amp;o=r2&amp;n=0.25" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img src="map.jpg" alt="caltopo map of trail"></a></p><p>The trail starts from Minaret Summit, a quick 10 minute drive from our house, which is why we pulled up late morning at 10am after a luxurious breakfast and coffee (I had kibble and water). The humans were strangely avoiding their computers this week, which ordinarily means spending every free moment climbing rock, but daiyi sprained a finger a couple days ago so we stuck to the ground this time.</p><p>During the forest trail, I ran laps around the humans and investigated the local wildlife!</p><p><img src="mica-digging.gif" alt="mica digging"></p><p>While trail planning, daiyi had misread the map thinking that the end of the OHV road was the end of the hike, so we only packed for 5 miles of water. Actually we were only halfway there! and at Deadman Pass is where the shadeless sand and scree slopes began. Luckily, I am a dog, so I didn’t get sand in my shoe like the humans did. Sandals not recommended.</p><p><img src="on-the-ridge.jpg" alt="mica on the ridge"></p><p>You can see the Minarets and Ritter and Banner on the opposing side of the valley for most of the ridge-top hike, they seemed to get closer and closer the entire time until you felt certain you would run right into them.</p><p>There was no water or snow except for a tiny patch on the side of the ridge, but I still found a couple mosquitos to snap at while the humans were stopped to eat their lunch burritos and plucots. The sun was out in full force, the sky was an uninterrupted blue. I was a hot dingo!</p><p><img src="hot-dingo.jpg" alt="mica seeking shade"></p><p>I sat down in the shade whenever I found the opportunity, but the humans kept us moving.</p><p>We reached the summit around 2pm.</p><p><img src="san-joaquin-summit.jpg" alt="mica on the summit of San Joaquin Mountain"></p><p>While the humans pointed their phones into the air and signed the summit register, I took a powernap in Marco’s shade.</p><p><img src="summit-register-nap.jpg" alt="mica sleeping under summit register"></p><p>I can’t read, but this is what they drew:</p><p><img src="summit-register.jpg" alt="our entry in the summit register"></p><p>Wait, we have to turn around?? Is this why the humans weren’t running circles the whole time like I was?</p><p>Here’s a view of the endless sandy ridge on the hike down:</p><p><img src="ridge-going-back.jpg" alt="sandy ridge"></p><p>That was my biggest day yet, but it’s only the beginning!</p><p><em>Edited: 2020-07-20</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2020/07/09/San-Joaquin-Mountain-My-first-SPS/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a dream sensation, life in berlin (2017)</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2018/09/26/a-dream-sensation-life-in-berlin/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2018/09/26/a-dream-sensation-life-in-berlin/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;Feeling feelings with higher highs and lower lowers in a place with actual seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;photo-section&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;photo-l
        
      
      </description>
      
      <enclosure url="http://daiyi.co/blog/tempelhof-daiyi-riding-bicycle.jpg" type="image" />
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Feeling feelings with higher highs and lower lowers in a place with actual seasons.</p><div class="photo-section">  <div class="photo-left-pull photo-small"><p><img src="jackpot-maschine-1.jpg" alt=""></p>  </div>  <br><br>  <br><br><p>Everyone eventually comes to Berlin, many will eventualy leave.</p><p>Malwine was telling me about Berlin syndrome where people who live there don’t get too attached because they know their friends will eventualy go.</p><div class="photo-section">  <div class="photo-right-pull photo-small"><p><img src="jackpot-maschine-2.jpg" alt=""></p>  </div><p>I spent a summer hanging out with clojure folks, drinking turkish coffee, and thinking about what I wanted to do with my time. Feeling free from a perscribed schedule to ride my bicycle and swim in the lakes outside the city, but missing something still. Picking up a lot of books, and trying to learn languages, calling home and catching up with friends far away, enjoying the dense german bread. Trying to unclench from a constant feeling of loss and guilt, and not being enough.</p>  </div></div><p>(I moved back to California in 2018.)</p><div class="photo-small"><p><img src="so-many-picnics.jpg" alt=""></p></div><p>(It’s February 2020 now as I find this in my neglected blog drafts. I can’t remember what I had tried to say before and what it meant to me, so I am looking at old photos and text journals and reading notes to pick up the pieces.)</p><p>(How can I forget the name of the park I lived next to and ran a triangle in so many mornings? the ubahn I took to the coworking space for clojurebridge meetings?)</p><div class="photo-section">  <div class="photo-right-pull"><p><img src="cycling-mitte.jpg" alt=""></p>  </div><blockquote><h5 id="20170727"><a class="header-anchor" href="#20170727">&gt;</a>20170727</h5><p>This morning I woke up an hour before my alarm and THE SKY WAS BLUE. It was supposed to rain the entire week so I immediately threw my stuff into my pack and went on an hour-long bike ride!</p></blockquote></div><p><img src="sketchbook-fall-cycling.jpg" alt=""></p><blockquote><h5 id="20170714"><a class="header-anchor" href="#20170714">&gt;</a>20170714</h5><p>Saskia talks a lot about mind/body balance, and it’s different words for one of my top concerns, except I say it like “I like cities, but I also need mountains”. The cities are full of people and jobs and programming communities and structure; the mountains is where I can move and breathe and be alone.</p></blockquote><p><img src="birthday.jpg" alt=""></p><div class="photo-left-pull"><p><img src="overgrown-back-courtyard.jpg" alt=""></p></div><br/><br/><blockquote><h5 id="20170811-F"><a class="header-anchor" href="#20170811-F">&gt;</a>20170811 F</h5><p>things Dave sent me to read:</p><ol><li><p>Kafka’s “before the law” &amp; companion</p></li><li><p>the opressiveness of structurelessness.</p></li></ol></blockquote><p><img src="tempelhof-daiyi-riding-bicycle.jpg" alt=""></p><div class="photo-section"><blockquote><h5 id="20170805"><a class="header-anchor" href="#20170805">&gt;</a>20170805</h5><p>Everything that’s excellent about me and that makes me happy I owe to being happy and having free time! Drawing as a kid, learning graphic design tools then a tablet with online tutorials, learning CSS and html then programming.</p><p>Today I put on my bathing suit and spend a couple hours fixing my bike. I unscrewed everything and now I see how the pieces go together. Not even feeling guilty for “wasting time” because I have enough of it! living slow = learning, exploring, creativity, expression.</p></blockquote>  <div class="photo-right-pull"><p><img src="bicycle-repair-bathroom-staging-area.jpg" alt=""></p>  </div></div><div class="photo-section">  <div class="photo-right-pull"><blockquote><h5 id="20170831"><a class="header-anchor" href="#20170831">&gt;</a>20170831</h5><p>I ran 5k today! It is my first 5k. […] But I did it! From now on all my runs will be 5k, which is “a short run” a la Noah Tye. I’ll run every other day. (:</p></blockquote>  </div></div><blockquote><h5 id="20170821"><a class="header-anchor" href="#20170821">&gt;</a>20170821</h5><p>“Emotional hurt is the price one has to pay in order to be independent. In certain areas of my life, I actively seek out solitude. Sometimes, however, this sense of isolation, like acid spilling out of a bottle, can unconsciously eat away at a person’s heart and dissolve it. You could see it, too, as a kind of double-edged sword. It protects me, but at the same time cuts away at me from the inside. I think in my own way I’m aware of this danger – probably through experience – and that’s why I’ve had to constantly keep my body in motion, in some cases pushing myself to the limit, in order to heal the loneliness I feel inside and put it in perspective. Not so much as an intentional act, but as an instinctive reaction. […] it’s like I can physically exhaust that portion of my discontent.”</p><p>– Haruki Murakami, <em>What I Talk About When I Talk About Running</em></p></blockquote><p><img src="monument.jpg" alt=""></p><blockquote><p>“I have wanted to kill myself a hundred times, but somehow I am still in love with life. This ridiculous weakness is perhaps one of our more stupid melancholy propensities, for is there anything more stupid than to be eager to go on carrying a burden which one would gladly throw away, to loathe one’s very being and yet to hold it fast, to fondle the snake that devours us until it has eaten our hearts away?”</p><p>– Voltaire, <em>Candide</em></p></blockquote><div class="photo-section">  <div class="photo-left-pull"><p><img src="tempelhof-garden.jpg" alt=""></p>  </div><blockquote><h5 id="20170909"><a class="header-anchor" href="#20170909">&gt;</a>20170909</h5><p>omfg curse John Furrow for getting me into Big Black Delta, I’ve been listening to Trágame Tierra, then BBD back to back to back to back all summer.</p></blockquote></div><p><br><br>I baked a lot because baking has always felt like a waste of time, and wasting time lavishly made me feel powerful and in control.</p><div class="photo-small"><p><img src="existential-baking.jpg" alt=""><br>(German quark cheese cake is really good, but you should just buy it at the store.)</p></div><blockquote><h5 id="20170829"><a class="header-anchor" href="#20170829">&gt;</a>20170829</h5><p>[…] (and all-time low for facebook/instagram though […] I’d gotten to the point last year where facebook was for seeing my friends’ mountain photos, and now those just make me sad)</p></blockquote><p><img src="critical-mass.jpg" alt=""></p><blockquote><h5 id="20170814-M"><a class="header-anchor" href="#20170814-M">&gt;</a>20170814 M</h5><p>I shouldn’t call my life boring, because it’s definitely not boring. It has the flavor of unremarkable that settles after solving all the problems. Maybe it’s because I’ve never not lived teetering on the brink of madness. I think I literally don’t know how to chill.</p></blockquote><div class="photos"><div class="photo"><p><img src="kreuzberg.jpg" alt=""></p></div><div class="photo"><p><img src="overgrown-bicycle.jpg" alt=""></p></div></div><blockquote><h5 id="20170912"><a class="header-anchor" href="#20170912">&gt;</a>20170912</h5><p>“I’d rather make money and spend it than make less money and try to figure out how to be tricky with it.” —dennis heihoff</p></blockquote><div class="photo-small"><p><img src="splits.jpg" alt=""></p></div><blockquote><p>&quot;No relation of a dream can convey that dream sensation. That commingling of absurdity, surprise and bewilderment in a tremor of struggling revolt. That notion of being captured by the incredible, which is the very essense of dreams.</p><p>It is impossible. It is impossible to convey the life sensation of any epic of one’s existence. That which makes its truth, its meaning, its subtle and penetrating essense. It is impossible.</p><p>We live as we dream, alone.&quot;</p><p>Joseph Conrad, <em>Heart of Darkness</em></p></blockquote><p><img src="kreuzberg-liminal-spaces.jpg" alt=""></p><p><em>Edited: 2020-02-27</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2018/09/26/a-dream-sensation-life-in-berlin/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a smol comic about clojure</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/07/19/a-smol-comic-about-clojure/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/07/19/a-smol-comic-about-clojure/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 06:20:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;clj_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;clj_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;clj_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;clj_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b
        
      
      </description>
      
      <enclosure url="http://daiyi.co/blog/clj_symbiot.jpg" type="image" />
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="clj_0.jpg" alt=""><br><img src="clj_1.jpg" alt=""><br><img src="clj_2.jpg" alt=""><br><img src="clj_3.jpg" alt=""></p><p><br><br></p><p>I made this cute comic because I’ve been writing a lot of clojure(/script) and people have been asking me about it so I’ve been introducing it a lot, and also holy crap a friend gifted me a graphics tablet over the weekend and I am finally reunited with digital art aaah :D :D :D</p><p>For those following along at home on shitty internet connections or screen readers or are struggling to parse my funky handwriting, I’ve transcribed the comic below!</p><h2 id="introducing-clojure-and-clojurescript"><a class="header-anchor" href="#introducing-clojure-and-clojurescript">&gt;</a>introducing clojure! (and clojurescript)</h2><p>(<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clojure" target="_blank" rel="noopener">clojure</a> says ♥, and clojurescript says ♥_BANG_ because alas, it has gone through the transpiler).</p><h3 id="clojure-is-a-dialect-of-lisp"><a class="header-anchor" href="#clojure-is-a-dialect-of-lisp">&gt;</a>clojure is a dialect of lisp.</h3><figure class="highlight clojure"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">&#123; <span class="symbol">:name</span>                <span class="string">"lisp"</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="symbol">:birth</span>               <span class="number">1958</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="symbol">:age</span>                 <span class="number">59</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="symbol">:typing</span>              [<span class="symbol">:strong</span> <span class="symbol">:dynamic</span>]</span><br><span class="line">  <span class="symbol">:favourite-ice-cream</span> <span class="string">"vanilla"</span>&#125;</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Cool thing I learned: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lisp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lisp</a> was the first (non-assembly) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-hosting" target="_blank" rel="noopener">self-hosted</a> language (it compiled itself!!)</p><figure class="highlight clojure"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">&#123; <span class="symbol">:name</span>                <span class="string">"clojure"</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="symbol">:birth</span>               <span class="number">2007</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="symbol">:age</span>                 <span class="number">10</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="symbol">:typing</span>              [<span class="symbol">:strong</span> <span class="symbol">:dynamic</span>]</span><br><span class="line">  <span class="symbol">:favourite-ice-cream</span> <span class="string">"raspberry cheesecake"</span>&#125;</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>(here I drew a lisp family tree, except the tree is an octopus)</p><h3 id="clojure-is-a-hosted-language"><a class="header-anchor" href="#clojure-is-a-hosted-language">&gt;</a>clojure is a hosted language.</h3><p>This means it is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commensalism" target="_blank" rel="noopener">symbiote</a> living on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_virtual_machine" target="_blank" rel="noopener">JVM</a> (Java Virtual Machine). Clojure can talk to its host with <a href="http://www.braveclojure.com/java/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">interop</a>. That means it can use its host’s libraries :D</p><p>(here I drew clojure as a mushroom, also a symbiote, whispering sweet interops into the ear of the JVM).</p><p>Clojure can target many things! We call it <a href="https://clojurescript.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">clojurescript</a> when it targets javascript. That means we can write clojure programs that work in the browser :D</p><p>(here I drew clojurescript also as a mushroom, lookin pretty chill on its host, javascript, console.log-ing, as one does.)</p><p>(I can’t believe I just spent my evening drawing clojure as various mushrooms…)</p><h3 id="choosing-a-text-editor-to-use-with-clojure-seems-to-be-something-people-think-deeply-about"><a class="header-anchor" href="#choosing-a-text-editor-to-use-with-clojure-seems-to-be-something-people-think-deeply-about">&gt;</a>choosing a text editor to use with clojure seems to be something people think deeply about.</h3><p>Lots of people like <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">emacs</a>.</p><p>I use <a href="https://atom.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Atom</a>.</p><p>As long as you’ve got something automatically minding your parens (e.g. <a href="https://shaunlebron.github.io/parinfer" target="_blank" rel="noopener">parinfer</a> or paredit) it’s probably fine. (here I drew a thumbs up, except the thumb is a face, and the face is saying “nice.”)</p><p>(extra note: if you decide to use emacs, don’t try to configure it from scratch like I did the first three times I tried to use emacs. go borrow <a href="https://github.com/jackrusher/dotemacs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">someone else</a>’s configuration!)</p><h3 id="why-would-anyone-use-clojure"><a class="header-anchor" href="#why-would-anyone-use-clojure">&gt;</a>why would anyone use clojure??</h3><ul><li>JVM<ul><li>lots of mature libraries from java</li><li>JVM abstracts away hardware &amp; OS</li></ul></li><li>concurrency<ul><li>clojure was designed for concurrency!</li></ul></li><li>lisp<ul><li>lisps are fun to write :D</li><li>functional programming is an interesting way to think</li><li>everything is data in clojure, which is a pattern really suited for some tasks</li><li>macros are powerful and fun!</li></ul></li><li>community ♥<ul><li>people are super friendly</li><li>you can directly talk with a lot of library maintainers and helpful folks in #clojurians slack channel</li><li>cozy local communities, such as in Berlin (:</li><li>ClojureBridge!!</li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="what-are-the-problems"><a class="header-anchor" href="#what-are-the-problems">&gt;</a>what are the problems?</h3><ul><li>it takes a while for your brain to adjust if you are coming from some languages.</li><li>the toolset and build process was a lot to take in at once (I’m still learning it…)</li><li>it’ll probably be a while before you’re comfortable enough to harness the full power of the language.</li><li>it’s really hard to make fan art because there are no animals or puns ):</li></ul><p>It’s okay! Just go have fun!</p><p>Also I’m super excited because Euroclojure is this week and it’s in Berlin! aaahh see you there?? (if you manage to find me and give me paper I’ll draw you hosting clojure as a mushroom, because I haven’t drawn enough mushrooms this week).</p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/07/19/a-smol-comic-about-clojure/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>so I can work longer, so I can earn more,</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/07/11/so-I-can-work-longer-so-I-can-earn-more/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/07/11/so-I-can-work-longer-so-I-can-earn-more/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 06:49:15 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;This song has been on my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player
        
      
      </description>
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This song has been on my mind.</p><iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/228441637&amp;color=00bb93&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false"></iframe><p>I will save you the experience of listening to it! Spoilers: it’s some trashy EDM about bottomless recursion:</p><blockquote><p>I do coke,<br>so I can work longer,<br>so I can earn more,<br>so I can do more coke.</p></blockquote><h2 id="—"><a class="header-anchor" href="#—">&gt;</a>—</h2><p>I was talking to someone I met at my first <a href="http://www.berlinminijam.de" target="_blank" rel="noopener">game jam</a> (!!!) last month, and he responded to my usual yearnings for mountains immediately by identifying it as an addiction. I felt pretty put off by this because addiction is a word for bad things, but a couple days later it came up in my thoughts again. I am dependent on movement and freedom for happiness and I feel withdrawal when I don’t have these things, no matter how many other social/intellectual/career/emotional/artistic needs I’m hitting.</p><blockquote><p>I <code>{ exercise | hang out in nature | chill in mountains }</code>,<br>so I can work longer,<br>so I can earn more,<br>so I can have longer gaps between soul-consuming full-time employment to <code>{ exercise | hang out in nature | chill in mountains }</code>.</p></blockquote><h2 id="—-v2"><a class="header-anchor" href="#—-v2">&gt;</a>—</h2><p>I am suspicious of a lot of the public concern over “work/life balance” and “self-care” and the entire category of nice words symbolising nice ideas that are starting to grate on me from corporate overuse. It’s to the industry’s benefit if people recursed between being healthy and working more, so they have their own non-selfless incentives to loudly wave around the banners of self-care.</p><p>Yes a lot of individuals actually care about taking care of themselves. But even then, to what end? I’m concerned that for a lot of people, there isn’t much more than</p><blockquote><p>I <code>maintain this meat vessel of my consciousness</code>,<br>so I can work longer,<br>so I can earn more,<br>so I can <code>continue maintaining this meat vessel of my consciousness</code>.</p></blockquote><p>We’re all robots already! Nothing has changed in the last milleniums, we’re still all shackled to labor except we’re shoveling digital dirt instead of moving around actual dirt. I think about my old landlord who made part of his living buying stuff for cheap on ebay and selling it again. This really shouldn’t be a thing people need to do, it’s just spinning wheels and it’s ridiculous!</p><p>We occasionally have some friends who leave their solid and stable white-collar office careers to be carpenters and farmers. This sounds super cute, but from my perspective, my dad spent most of his life working his ass off to not be a carpenter and farmer. This context makes these things a little weird for me.</p><p>At this point I think I’m solidly in softcore existential crisis mode :^) Anyway I’m having a lot of fun learning clojurescript</p><figure class="highlight clojure"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">(<span class="name"><span class="builtin-name">defn</span></span> freedom []</span><br><span class="line">  (<span class="name"><span class="builtin-name">cons</span></span> (<span class="name">rand-nth</span> [<span class="symbol">:nature</span> <span class="symbol">:mountains</span> <span class="symbol">:movement</span>]) (<span class="name"><span class="builtin-name">lazy-seq</span></span> (<span class="name">freedom</span>))))</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">(<span class="name"><span class="builtin-name">defn</span></span> life []</span><br><span class="line">  (<span class="name"><span class="builtin-name">cons</span></span> (<span class="name"><span class="builtin-name">cons</span></span> <span class="symbol">:work</span> (<span class="name"><span class="builtin-name">take</span></span> <span class="number">5</span> (<span class="name">freedom</span>))) (<span class="name">life</span>)))</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">(<span class="name">life</span>)</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Clojure(/script) is a language and toolchain that I keep forgetting no one actually knows about because I spent most of my time these days deeply lodged in the loving nest of the clojure community. When I crawl out of this nest I get a lot of scepticism concerning my current life trajectory, like “why would you spend so much time on such an obscure thing when you could be learning a useful skill???” (the same flavour of scepticism I got a lot in Serbia where locals I met were like “why did you come here if you could literally go anywhere???”)</p><p>On one hand, why do anything at all? jkjk I’m not actually a nihilist those people are terrifying. The process of learning a language/toolchain/specialisation is transferable and does feel less insurmountable and more efficient every time, so there’s that clasic “learning to learn” thing. But also learning itself has intrinsic value, kinda like how art has intrinsic value because we decided so.</p><p>Learning, like art and music and socialising and mountains, fills in the spaces between <code>maintaining the meat vessel of your consciousness</code> and <code>work</code>ing, to make things nice.</p><p>It’s fun.</p><p>I have to be careful about trying to have too much fun.</p><p><img src="20170710.jpg" alt="comic"></p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/07/11/so-I-can-work-longer-so-I-can-earn-more/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What am I reading? (April/May 2017)</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/06/12/What-am-I-reading-April-May-2017/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/06/12/What-am-I-reading-April-May-2017/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 23:38:05 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;velika-paklenica-sketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sketch of velika paklenica&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sketch of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikip
        
      
      </description>
      
      <enclosure url="http://daiyi.co/blog/velika-paklenica-sketch.jpg" type="image" />
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><p><img src="velika-paklenica-sketch.jpg" alt="sketch of velika paklenica"></p><figcaption><p>Sketch of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paklenica" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Velika Paklenica</a> in the Dinaric Alps, from a house on the mountain where I took shelter from thunder &amp; lightning storms (:</p></figcaption></figure><p>I spent the last two months “traveling” in the Balkans (to be detailed in a separate post!)</p><p>If you know me, you know I travel in a pretty dumb way that is not exactly relaxing. My reading habits were a lot more erratic than when I was in a winter coma in Brooklyn; the cracks of idle time I’d been training myself to spend on books instead of flipping through social stuff on my phone got redelegated to things like staring at OSM, sending couchsurfing emails, and trying to figure out how to pronounce stuff in Serbian.</p><h3 id="Wikipedia"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Wikipedia">&gt;</a>Wikipedia!</h3><p>Oh, and reading cached Wikipedia pages of local/regional history/geology! which was such a great idea, it was the first trip I’ve done something like that and I would definitely recommend it.</p><p>In fact it was such a good exercise that I went back and cached the Wikipedia pages for places I’m quite familiar with. Notable selection: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_hills_in_San_Francisco" target="_blank" rel="noopener">list of hills in SF</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geology_of_the_Yosemite_area" target="_blank" rel="noopener">geology of the Yosemite area</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/California_Water_Wars" target="_blank" rel="noopener">California water wars</a>. (also I found <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Giant_Rock" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this</a> … and here’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slab_City,_California" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a classic</a>). (This wikidive is starting to inspire a roadtrip). (GREAT now I’m homesick for California :U )</p><p>And here’s the actual books I managed to read in my two months of tramping!</p><h3 id="Savage-Theories-–-Pola-Oloixarac-2008"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Savage-Theories-–-Pola-Oloixarac-2008">&gt;</a><em>Savage Theories</em> – Pola Oloixarac (2008)</h3><p><b>genre</b>  postmodern magical realism?<br><b>tldr;</b>  weird as hell, 10/10 would recommend</p><p>Pola Oloixarac is like Argentinian <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Foster_Wallace" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DFW</a>-lite. The entire time my brain was casually like “what the fuck is this shit” yet also strangely enjoying it. If you like David Foster Wallace/postmodern lit, you’ll know what I mean. If you don’t, you might not like this book, it is weird as hell. Try it! It’s a smashing and violent smorgasbord of the Buenos Aires alternative scene, evolution theories/philosophy, Argentinian history, and idk, how weird people can be.</p><h3 id="The-Handmaid’s-Tale-–-Margaret-Atwood-1985"><a class="header-anchor" href="#The-Handmaid’s-Tale-–-Margaret-Atwood-1985">&gt;</a><em>The Handmaid’s Tale</em> – Margaret Atwood (1985)</h3><p><b>genre</b>  speculative fiction, dystopian<br><b>tldr;</b>  good but (unpopular opinion?) like contemporary-junk-food-fic-good, e.i. Hunger Games</p><p>This was my first Margaret Atwood book!</p><p>I picked this up last winter because a lot of noise was made around the TV adaptation, and just got around to actually reading it.</p><p>My favourite part was seeing hints of the underlying 80’s feminist attitudes. I am such a fan of the meta-context of social-commentary-fic along with the context in the fics themselves! but maybe that’s just me being young and not having yet experienced much history myself. I like to imagine future kids reading fic from nowadays and being fascinated by contemporary SJW attitudes, ha.</p><p>The epilogue was a bit awkward, I thought it took away from the uncertainty and wispy dystopian feel of the story by contextualising it too much. I’d suggest not reading it and pretending it doesn’t exist :D Also check out the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Handmaid' target="_blank" rel="noopener"s_Tale">wikipedia page</a> after, it has some interesting info.</p><h3 id="Letters-to-a-Young-Muslim-–-Omar-Saif-Ghobash-2017"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Letters-to-a-Young-Muslim-–-Omar-Saif-Ghobash-2017">&gt;</a><em>Letters to a Young Muslim</em> – Omar Saif Ghobash (2017)</h3><p><b>genre</b>  non-fic, semi-autobiographical, culture, Islam<br><b>tldr;</b>  would recommend!</p><p>This was notably my first audio book ever. I “read” it on the bus from London to Edinburgh, because the air conditioning was drying out my contacts and I had to keep my eyes closed. This experience has relaxed my suspicion of audiobooks, or maybe this was just the perfect candidate: it’s written in second person, literally letters from the author to his sons, and narrated by the author himself, which made for a really good listen.</p><p>He talks a lot about his own life, a slice into the middle east for someone (me) who has very little context into what that’s like. At first I was like <em>ugh, this book would be so different if he had daughters to write to</em>, but then he addresses that too! I really really like how he urges his kids &amp; country to recontextualise their culture in the modern globalised world, to express themselves in productive ways, take responsibility for the good and bad things of their culture, and to create contemporary and relatable art and media. His optimistic and practical attitude was really heartening. And he communicates these thoughts really well (I can’t do it justice with a summary), like I almost want to take his ideas, generalise them a bit, and send them to my parents.</p><h3 id="Babel-17-–-Samuel-R-Delany-1966"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Babel-17-–-Samuel-R-Delany-1966">&gt;</a><em>Babel-17</em> – Samuel R. Delany (1966)</h3><p><b>genre</b>  OG sci-fi, micro space opera<br><b>tldr;</b>  groundbreaking sci-fi for its time, and aged well :D</p><p>Don’t read plot summaries for this! because it was really interesting to work out what the story was getting at about language and how it shapes thoughts, especially keeping in mind this was written in the 60’s. Apparently this story influenced a lot of sci-fi down the line, so reading this was a bit of a temporal pilgrimage in my favourite genre (:</p><h3 id="The-Man-Who-Was-Thursday-–-G-K-Chesterton-1908"><a class="header-anchor" href="#The-Man-Who-Was-Thursday-–-G-K-Chesterton-1908">&gt;</a><em>The Man Who Was Thursday</em> – G. K. Chesterton (1908)</h3><p><b>genre</b>  “metaphysical thriller”; police and anarchists being silly<br><b>tldr;</b>  It was fun!</p><p>Following <a href="http://www.daiyi.co/blog/2017/03/31/What-am-I-reading-March-2017/#A-Tree-Grows-In-Brooklyn-Betty-Smith-1943" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>A Tree Grows In Brooklyn</em></a> while living in Brooklyn, I’ve been keen to read books set in the places I’m traveling to. While in London I’d remembered that Ilana had recommended <em>The Man Who Was Thursday</em> back when I saw her last December. It’s not really the type of book I usually read but I found myself enjoying it!</p><p>It involves turn of the century shenanigans of classically serious institutions (police? anarchists??) who were trying super hard to take things seriously, but things kept going spectacularly wrong in absurd twists. It seemed to be some sort of meta-satire, a short and fun read, different tone/mood that what I usually go for but I’d recommend it!</p><h3 id="Borges-A-Personal-Anthology-–-Jorge-Luis-Borges-1961"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Borges-A-Personal-Anthology-–-Jorge-Luis-Borges-1961">&gt;</a><em>Borges: A Personal Anthology</em> – Jorge Luis Borges (1961)</h3><p><b>genre</b>  short stories, mostly set in Argentina<br><b>tldr;</b>  very dreamy and I found it hard to focus while reading them, but they tend to be pretty good, yet oddly not completely satisfying, but I think this is the point.</p><blockquote><p>On the second floor, on the top story, the house seemed to be infinite and growing. <em>The house is not this large</em>, he thought. <em>It is only made larger by the penumbra, the symmetry, the mirrors, the years, my ignorance, the solitude.</em></p></blockquote><p>These are the topics Wikipedia says Borges writes about: dreams, labyrinths, libraries, mirrors, fictional writers, philosophy, and religion. This is a pretty rad aesthetic. I found it to be pretty accurate in this collection of short stories by Borges assembled by Borges, an early writer of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magic_realism" target="_blank" rel="noopener">magical realism</a>.</p><p>Because of the magical realism and short stories, I couldn’t help but compare this to García Márquez’s Strange Pilgrims which I <a href="http://www.daiyi.co/blog/2017/03/31/What-am-I-reading-March-2017/#Strange-Pilgrims-Gabriel-Garcia-Marquez-1970-80" target="_blank" rel="noopener">read the month before</a>. I don’t know why, but I found García Márquez’s world a lot more satisfying, like nice popping sounds and things fitting into things type of satisfying. While I also liked these stories by Borges, they felt a lot more ethereal. Or maybe it was me, having been on the road for a while, projecting my losing of my sense of self (to be revisited in a future blog post :P) onto the stories. Definitely worth a read either way!</p><p>(Unforunately I accidentally returned the kindle library book before I got to save my bookmarks/notes so I can’t recommend the titles of my favourite stories.) But there’s a quote that accurately describes my feels sometimes that I’d had the forethought to have screenshotted:</p><blockquote><p>In the days and nights which followed the operation he came to realise that he had merely been, up until then, in a suburb of hell.</p></blockquote><h3 id="A-Problem-From-Hell-America-and-the-Age-of-Genocide-–-Samantha-Power-2002"><a class="header-anchor" href="#A-Problem-From-Hell-America-and-the-Age-of-Genocide-–-Samantha-Power-2002">&gt;</a><em>A Problem From Hell: America and the Age of Genocide</em> – Samantha Power (2002)</h3><p><b>genre</b>  non-fic, history, foreign policy<br><b>tldr;</b>  quite long and well-researched, if you’re interested in this topic this is the book to read</p><blockquote><p>&quot;From now on no government may kill off a large block of its own subjects or citizens of any country with impunity.”</p></blockquote><p>I mentioned I’d been reading a lot of Wikipedia history pages, so I caught up on a lot of Balkan history (and refreshed on WWI/WWII history, which is a topic of focus in a lot of European museums). I’d grown up with my mom heavily criticising our liberal American history classes for glossing over the Japanese occupation of China (which heavily affected her life), and to my <em>horror and embarassement</em> there seems to be an entire stack of more genocides I’d failed to learn very much about in school.</p><p>It’s cool, I’ve gone about fixing this. The first part of the book is about the Armenian Genocide and Holocaust leading up to this guy Raphael Lemkin devoting his life to outlawing genocide (he invented the word so people could wrap their brains around the idea) and how resistant world leaders were to ratifying this. It sucks that it has to be this way, but I can understand why. Like, what are we supposed to do?? You (a major world power) can’t not intervene because that is horrific, but intervening also causes all sorts of unintended destructive perturbation (I heard a lot of first hand accounts of this while traveling in the Balkans last month). Genocide is the titular “problem from hell” because you’re fucked either way.</p><p>The book is good, maybe even <em>too</em> good. It’s quite long, very well researched, many shocking primary sources (e.i. I can’t believe a person in this century believed this thing and said these words about human beings), and not exactly the kind of subject matter you can binge. I haven’t finished it.</p><p>Anyway. Heavy shit for the summer. I’ll probably skip to the second part that goes over historical accounts of genocide in Cambodia, Iraq, Bosnia, Rwanda and Kosovo (or skim on wikipedia) because I’m halfway through and it hasn’t recommended any actionable items, and there’s no happy endings, so I guess I’m just here for the history.</p><h3 id="Kindred-–-Octavia-Bulter-1979"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Kindred-–-Octavia-Bulter-1979">&gt;</a><em>Kindred</em> – Octavia Bulter (1979)</h3><p><b>genre</b>  extremely soft sci-fi, basically sci-fi brie, maybe sci-fi cream cheese<br><b>tldr;</b>  enjoyable pop fiction</p><p>It feels like pop fiction so I read it quickly, but it’s interesting to note that it was written in the 70s (the civil rights movement was in the 50s-60s). It’s about an American black woman who uncontrollably flickers between her present-day 70s to (oh no) a plantation in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plantation_era" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Antebellum</a> South. My first Octavia Butler book, and I’d take recommendations for similar authors \o/</p><h3 id="Essays-–-Ralph-Waldo-Emerson-mid-1800s"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Essays-–-Ralph-Waldo-Emerson-mid-1800s">&gt;</a><em>Essays</em> – Ralph Waldo Emerson (mid-1800s)</h3><p><b>genre</b>  essays<br><b>tldr;</b>  aahh…</p><p>Ok so I love nature and my life is basically man vs nature, so I expected to like reading Ralph Waldo Emerson. Turns out this writing is SUPER HARD TO READ, or maybe I’ve slowly become illiterate over the years since I’ve left high school. I shamefully prefer Wikipedia summaries of this beliefs and ideas over his actual writing. (Then again, I end up feeling similarly to most philosophers I’ve attempted to read). I made it about halfway through <em>On Self-Reliance</em>, but maybe it was because of insufficient coffee! We’ll try again next month \o/</p><h3 id="Whewww"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Whewww">&gt;</a>Whewww.</h3><p>Embarrassingly I don’t think I read a single book while I was in Croatia (the last two weeks of my trip).</p><p>It’s June! Holy shit. Where is the year going?? As of a week ago I’m back in steady-state city-life and finding myself super pleased with this thing where I’m not checking the <a href="https://misportal.hcr.hr/HCRweb/faces/simple/Map.jspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mine map</a> for mines or memorising the names of the small towns between where I am and where I need to be or crash-coursing the Cyrillic alphabet (twice, after realising the neighboring country uses it slightly different). It’s kind of nice to sit down at a COMPUTER and type at a KEYBOARD.</p><p>I know, my dear readers are mostly office potatoes jealously eyeing my life of wild abandon but the point of all that was to remind me about the virtues of having a solid career :P And it worked! I’ll be sitting in offices all summer and I’m pretty excited about it, which was not an attitude I could see myself having last year when I was doing exactly that. I’ve got the sleeping on benches and camping in snow all out of my system and am pleased to rejoin society and partake in regular showers and non-disposable friendships.</p><p>Anyway, say hi if you’re in Berlin, I don’t have the budget to eat out but we can enjoy the LOVELY, PREDICTABLE, SUNNY BERLIN WEATHER with a park/canal/river stroll or you can come over and I can test my vegetarian cooking on you :D :D :D</p><p>And to conclude, a toast to a temporary end to my travels, here’s some thoughts from Borges on mortality:</p><blockquote><p>There is a nearby street forbidden to my step,<br>There is a mirror that has seen me for the last time,<br>There is a door I have shut until the end of the world.<br>Among the books in my library<br>There are some I shall never reopen.</p><p><cite>(Limits, Borges)</cite></p></blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/06/12/What-am-I-reading-April-May-2017/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What am I reading? (March 2017)</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/03/31/What-am-I-reading-March-2017/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/03/31/What-am-I-reading-March-2017/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 06:02:41 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;Oh you know me, I only do things intensely. I’m either super into a book or throwing it away with disgust. \o/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;The-Best-We-Co
        
      
      </description>
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oh you know me, I only do things intensely. I’m either super into a book or throwing it away with disgust. \o/</p><h3 id="The-Best-We-Could-Do-Thi-Bui-2016"><a class="header-anchor" href="#The-Best-We-Could-Do-Thi-Bui-2016">&gt;</a><em>The Best We Could Do</em> - Thi Bui (2016)</h3><p><em>genre</em>  graphic memoir<br><em>tldr;</em>  MOST EXCELLENT, READ ASAP</p><p>This is a deeply personal graphic novel memoir about the complicated thing that is motherhood/daughterhood, churned up with living under communism, fleeing as refugees, and the dynamics of an immigrant family in America. I walked into a Barnes &amp; Noble on the way back from teaching one day (partly for the novelty of being inside a physical Barnes &amp; Noble in 2017) and picked this up randomly (or due to excellent strategic storefront arrangement/curation), and this is how I ended up crying in a Barnes &amp; Noble in the year 2017 of Luigi.</p><p>On one hand I feel like I can’t claim so much emotional reverb from this story because my own parents immigrated in a completely different way, but the ways in which we struggle to express our love and understanding for each other felt distressingly similar.</p><p>As with <em>The Brief and Wondrous Life of Oscar Wao</em> which I read last month, I learned a lot of political history on the side of a thrilling/heart-rending story, this time about Vietnam. Also the art is REALLY GOOD. Thi Bui is amazing. Also I saw that she is living in the Bay Area (Berkeley!)</p><p><em>how to read this book</em>: with emotional fortitude.</p><h3 id="Strange-Pilgrims-Gabriel-Garcia-Marquez-1970-80"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Strange-Pilgrims-Gabriel-Garcia-Marquez-1970-80">&gt;</a><em>Strange Pilgrims</em> - Gabriel García Márquez (1970-80)</h3><p><em>genre</em>  short stories<br><em>tldr;</em>  enchanting, quick and satisfying vignettes, highly recommended!</p><p>García Márquez brings a sleepy dream of Latin American magic to stately Old World settings. Languid characters with jobs like singer and writer and magician living fantastic lives and feeling one thing at a time. The short story format is pretty righteous. The author has a certain way of describing people and circumstance that makes them feel tragically incidental yet fated with purpose.</p><p>I think my favourite was “I Only Came to Use the Phone”, but honestly they’re all so wonderful!</p><p><em>how to read this book</em>: a lovely interlude between your other heavy world-weary and technical reads.</p><h3 id="A-Tree-Grows-In-Brooklyn-Betty-Smith-1943"><a class="header-anchor" href="#A-Tree-Grows-In-Brooklyn-Betty-Smith-1943">&gt;</a><em>A Tree Grows In Brooklyn</em> - Betty Smith (1943)</h3><p><em>genre</em>  historic fiction<br><em>tldr;</em>  poverty and desperation + hope &amp; the pre-WWI american dream. it’s…really good.</p><p>This was a nice read after living on Brooklyn. I imagined the Williamsburg streets I walked and biked past all winter, a hundred years ago, right before the first world war. I’m having trouble writing this review, I think it’s because I have too many feelings ahh!</p><p>This is another immigrant story of a family navigating the unwieldy projection of parents wishing their kids to do better than themselves. (If you’ve been following along my monthly book reviews, this is totally an accidental theme).</p><p>The Nolans are poor and hungry and struggle to make rent, but are rich in song and laughing and stories and imagination, which made their lives bearable.</p><p>A lot of the problems on the minds of their people are still relevant – why are we so cruel to each other when our hardships should bring us together? why do we work so much and have so little time for ourselves? Is there anything more to life than this work/struggle/raise-family/work/die cycle, and how can we break it? It talks about poverty, race, education, family, and life meaning, in a way that I found endearing because I picked this up on recommendation from Connie a lot of years ago rather than was forcibly made to read it in high school to extract the human condition. I think you may like it, too (:</p><p>I loved that the characters are really strong! Both in character, and in the way they are written. Also lots of good strong coffee in this book.</p><p>The writing style is simple, a clean transmission of emotions and feelings and musing and hope directly from the characters to your brain in a way that thoughtleaders/marriage counselors only wish they could communicate.</p><p><em>how to read this book</em>: it’s an easy read, any time is a good time \o/</p><p><em>disclaimer</em>: this book is heavily gender-roletastic, because it was written in the 40s about 1900-10s. I usually find gender-role stuff pretty unbearable, but reading this with the time context I felt completely ok and even kind of illuminated.</p><h3 id="The-Confidence-Code-Katty-Kay-Claire-Shipman-2015"><a class="header-anchor" href="#The-Confidence-Code-Katty-Kay-Claire-Shipman-2015">&gt;</a><em>The Confidence Code</em> - Katty Kay &amp; Claire Shipman (2015)</h3><p><em>genre</em>  business/careers<br><em>tldr;</em>  Awkward and not helpful. Did not finish.</p><p>This book is about women and confidence in the workplace. I picked it up from the library because the <a href="http://www.shenomads.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SheNomads</a> book club was reading it, but I couldn’t get through it. I found it blandly and unnecessarily heteronormative for something published in 2015, repetitive (more suited as a longform blog post rather than a book), and the stories and cases and studies collected didn’t feel necessarily more useful than like, your average 3 hours of browsing specific subreddits/twitter circles. Or 5 minutes of talking to any woman who has worked a job.</p><p>Maybe it’s for the people who don’t live in those parts of the internet, or haven’t any older women in their lives? I can vaguely see the appeal.</p><p>Either way, it needs actionable items. The writing style is cringey and heavy-handed at times, and early chapters are windy and unfocused.</p><p><em>how to read this book</em>: skim a summary.</p><p>–</p><p>And that’s it for March! I’m going without my laptop in April and most of May, but will hopefully have lots of time to read while on the road. chau o/</p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/03/31/What-am-I-reading-March-2017/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a tiny life in brooklyn winter</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/03/21/a-tiny-winter-life-in-brooklyn/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/03/21/a-tiny-winter-life-in-brooklyn/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 06:51:15 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;Three months later and I’m taking down my wall tapestries again, leaving the climbing gym where I’ve made friends with the regulars chara
        
      
      </description>
      
      <enclosure url="http://daiyi.co/blog/f-train.jpg" type="image" />
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three months later and I’m taking down my wall tapestries again, leaving the climbing gym where I’ve made friends with the regulars characters and routesetters, the cafes I work at often enough that they recognise my mannerisms but not enough that they remember my name, my tiny job, my tiny bike.</p><div class="photo-right-pull"><p><img src="the-cliffs-snow.jpg" alt="snow outside The Cliffs"></p></div><p>I came to New York with high hopes of learning fun computery things at recurse center and ice climbing upstate – I was rejected from rc, and found myself in the shortest and most indecisive, un-ice-forming conditions of northeast winter season in recent memory.</p><p>I did manage a lot of computery things on my own, was <em>super lucky</em> to have met excellent people who went out of their way to include me in their lives, and did some maintenance work on the fear and anxiety I occasionally accumulate around intellectual vulnerability and feeling competent if I’m not vigilant. I read a lot of books.</p><p>I think it was an ok way to spend some time.</p><div class="photo-small"><p><img src="rooftop-snow.jpg" alt="snow on the roofs"></p></div><p>In December I was in San Diego tessellating my objects into two checked bags, thinking I’d go live in New York for a long time. Metal and rope are bad at compressing so most of it was climbing and backpacking stuff by volume, but I did manage a few nice books too (:</p><p>I’m leaving having touched none of my gear, which I’m a tiny bit sad about. I marathoned the five-hour public transit daytrips up the Hudson every weekend the first month in a vague attempt at being in mountains before giving in to the cityfolk winter vegetable aesthetic.</p><p>I met Kat, another in the increasingly large fraction of my friends who have trucks and vans that they live out of, who hosted a gathering of mountain folks in a lovely cabin in the woods.</p><p><img src="cabin.jpg" alt="cabin in the woods"></p><p>Kat knew the Hudson River Valley and took me around in her truck, and I felt that I was first coming to understand New York through an outskirter’s perspective. We hiked some Hudson classics that the internet had warned me would be swarming with humans, but we found enchantingly lonely in the winter.</p><p>We ran into some friendly cave folks who taught us some caving basics! Ugh cavers are so cool. It was pretty rad fiddling with cave gear coming from a climbing background, comparing notes of all the similar but slightly different, specially adapted gadgets.</p><p>Kat left for her cave job in Oregon and I fell into a New York City winter coma.</p><p><img src="hart.jpg" alt="a winter forest in our home"></p><p>Housing in Brooklyn is somewhat affordable in a way that is unreal to a recent San Francisco/Bay alumn. My flatmates and neighbors are all friends with each other and form a loose family of sorts, with proper killswitches for introvert personal-time needs. Commonspaces are lovely with plants and kitchens are stocked and the house is warm and smells like cooking. This is what I’m going to miss most about here.</p><p>I don’t understand why simple habits take a different shape around each place. You’d think a urgency for caffeine would overcome physical continuity, but in this iteration of home, the aeropress and handgrinder I’d been so excited about and had used every day in Berlin lay untouched in the cabinet.</p><p><img src="f-train.jpg" alt="f train"></p><p>I live close to the subway, but a round trip costs a pint of nice ice cream (even in winter I compare the emotional value of my spendings against ice cream). I agonised over bleeding money from public transit and torturing my eyeballs from riding high speeds at freezing, but after going down a brief wormhole about vintage frames I nabbed a deal on craigslist.</p><p><strong>BIKES ARE THE BEST.</strong></p><p>So much ambient anxiety about my life choices dissipated after I regained wheeled status \o/ I need a hammerspace bike to explore the world with.</p><p><img src="east-river-park.jpg" alt="f train"></p><p>A friend I’ll miss along with my human friends, this little red aluminum bicycle that happens to be the same age as me, my adventure twin.</p><p>I’d originally been planning to travel in south america during the nothern hemisphere’s winter months, but after the election in November I felt so guilty for being in a selfish phase of my life that I decided to go to New York instead, to put my skills to work against something that felt so big and ominous and uncertain and terrible. We went to meetups and rallies and marches and talks and hackathons. I don’t think I accomplished anything in particular. I feel pretty ineffective in general.</p><div class="photos"><div class="photo"><p><img src="womens-march.jpg" alt="women's march nyc"></p></div><div class="photo"><p><img src="hack-the-ban.jpg" alt="hack the ban"></p></div></div><p>In the end I spent most of my time being selfish anyway. After two weeks of deeply inspecting and making web tools and demos and builds for the first time I feel like I’m on the verge of not being a poser when I tell people I’m a frontend engineer. I think I’m starting to understand one reason people like school: it’s a place where learning doesn’t feel weirdly self-indulgent. It is a context for guilt-free exploration, where the world waits patiently as you take and take and build the potential to give back. Stay in school, kids.</p><p>Time is going by too quickly for how much novelty I’m desperately shoveling into my human experience. Many things are happening, and a lot of them don’t feel real. It hasn’t registered that I’m going to be in Romania in a week and a half, not because it’s particularly shocking, but because it seems reasonable enough that it doesn’t require a second thought.</p><p>I was obsessive about spending my time as efficiently as possible when I set out on this nomadic year, but by now much of my anxieties over efficiency have been replaced by <em>I need nature asap</em> and <em>but I also need my computer because my brain is marinating in computery things!!</em> I’m feeling the multitude of narratives that is me fighting for dominance, and of the many things humans are good at multitasking is critically low on the list. This is something my brother says, and it’s been on my mind a lot. But how do I pick one thing when <em>everything is interesting?</em></p><p>These days I keep going back and forth between being really excited to be on the road again and seeing friends and reading and learning and chasing opportunities, and being exhausted from being excited about things.</p><p><img src="rocks-cityskyline.jpg" alt="central park sunset with snowy rocks"></p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/03/21/a-tiny-winter-life-in-brooklyn/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What am I reading? (February 2017)</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/03/01/What-am-I-reading-February-2017/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/03/01/What-am-I-reading-February-2017/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:16:59 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;I didn’t get through much this month because I’m reading Modern Operating Systems in slow motion and Seveneves took forever, but here are the books I read in February! Part of an &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/categories/what-am-I-reading&quot;&gt;ongoing series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
      
      </description>
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I didn’t get through much this month because I’m reading Modern Operating Systems in slow motion and Seveneves took forever, but here are the books I read in February! Part of an <a href="/blog/categories/what-am-I-reading">ongoing series</a>.</p><a id="more"></a><h3 id="The-Brief-and-Wondrous-Life-of-Oscar-Wao-Junot-Diaz"><a class="header-anchor" href="#The-Brief-and-Wondrous-Life-of-Oscar-Wao-Junot-Diaz">&gt;</a>The Brief and Wondrous Life of Oscar Wao - Junot Díaz</h3><h4 id="fiction-really-good"><a class="header-anchor" href="#fiction-really-good">&gt;</a>fiction | really good!</h4><p>tldr: READ IT IT IS GOOD. HOly shit this book was turned up to 11. Completely unapologetically crass and carnal narration, chaotic bouncing around to different pov and people until the narrator materialises within the story themself. Intense, headstrong and tragic characters charging directly into anguish. Maybe because I was raised under a rock in upper middle class white suburbia but this book was bleeding a vibe and culture and a completely different way of experiencing america/the world than I’ve ever seen or heard and I liked that so much. And maybe the most surprising part that I didn’t bargain for but was amazed by, a stern talking-to about my ignorance of and catchup with a particularly brutal part of Dominican history, dictatorship under the Trujillo cult of personality. 1000/10 it’s a good dog read this book!!</p><p><em>How to read this book</em>: with wikipedia on hand for historic sidetrips!</p><h3 id="Seveneves-Neal-Stephenson"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Seveneves-Neal-Stephenson">&gt;</a>Seveneves - Neal Stephenson</h3><h4 id="speculative-sci-fi-I-liked-it"><a class="header-anchor" href="#speculative-sci-fi-I-liked-it">&gt;</a>speculative sci-fi | I liked it</h4><p>All in all middle-of-the-road Stephenson; it’s a single threaded plotline with fast paced edge-tickling action cut with long, more boring analysis/gratuitous description of random pieces of technology.</p><p>I can see some people being super into the future-tech deep dives but I just came here for the philosophical thought experiments about future human societies. The thought experiments are super interesting!</p><p>Some of the book is maneuvering the situation as to set up the various thought experiments so it does give off a bit of feeling contrived, and more softer scifi. I recognised this trade-off and felt pretty forgiving. I’d recommend this book if you like Stephenson, but if you’re new to Stephenson you should probably read Snow Crash or something instead!</p><p><em>How to read this book</em>: play along with the thought experiments and have a discussion buddy as you read; reading this book definitely felt more satisfying when I had someone to talk/rant about the ideas in it with.</p><p>Also DON’T READ the back cover summary (and I’m not even a person who cares about plot twists). It’s more motivating get through such a long book if you have no idea what’s going on :D</p><h3 id="Nonviolent-Communication-Marshall-B-Rosenberg"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Nonviolent-Communication-Marshall-B-Rosenberg">&gt;</a>Nonviolent Communication - Marshall B. Rosenberg</h3><h4 id="non-fic-I’d-recommend-it"><a class="header-anchor" href="#non-fic-I’d-recommend-it">&gt;</a>non-fic | I’d recommend it</h4><p>I like how this book formalises a lot of ideas I have floating around in my head about how to meet people where they are at emotionally, expressing your own needs in terms of actionable items, etc. (a whole 'nother topic for another time). I like comparing it against <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/769016.How_to_Talk_So_Kids_Will_Listen_Listen_So_Kids_Will_Talk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How to Talk So Kids Will Listen and Listen So Kids Will Talk</a>, which has similar axioms but angles it more towards parenting/interacting with children (which is really powerful for communicating with adults sometimes).</p><p>I’ve started teaching again this month and have gotten some nice reminders that putting these ideas to practice is a muscle I must constantly flex (like how I am starting to injure my back while climbing because I’m out of bouldering shape, oops).</p><p>Incidentally, I’ve also had a couple of encounters with adults that really put me in my place in terms of my wild expectations for how I can make my life better from self-improvement. (If people are super mad and feel entitled to making you miserable, it takes a better person than me to not regress to profuse apology in order to make them go away and stop yelling at me. Fuck that noise. I’m tired of people telling me I need to be kinder and more understanding and more gentle. That’s the case for the kids I teach, with my family, my friends, my peers and colleagues. If someone approaches you with the attitude that you are lesser than them sometimes there’s nothing you can do to convince them to respect and consider you as an equal. If a rando doesn’t want to be reasoned with FUCK them, that is super not ok and I will not be cornered into emotional prostration.)</p><p><em>How to read this book</em>: I find it really helpful to take bullet notes as I’m reading. I’ve discovered that I really need to jot down specific examples of phrases and words when reading these types of books, because the examples tend to illustrate ideas better than describing them in abstract.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/03/01/What-am-I-reading-February-2017/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>notes from a civic hackathon</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/02/26/notes-from-a-civic-hackathon/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/02/26/notes-from-a-civic-hackathon/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 11:34:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hacktheban.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Hack The Ban&lt;/a&gt; was an anomaly among tech events, with a focus on b
        
      
      </description>
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.hacktheban.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hack The Ban</a> was an anomaly among tech events, with a focus on building relationships between local activist groups and the local tech community. Though the event was formed in response to the immigration executive order, organisations representing immigration rights/marginalised communities have existed for a very long time. Startup folk have an impulse to prop up new solutions when they see problems, which is great in many cases, but sometimes it is also worth considering joining forces with organisations that have intimate ties with and understanding of the community they are serving, a decade of work, and a diversity of skillsets and backgrounds and experiences.</p><p>Because it was a single day event, there was no sleep deprivation necessary, and due to the motivation/theme, the usual competitive factor that makes ordinary hackathons unappealing to some types of people (me!) was noticeably absent. Everyone wins at a civic hackathon (:</p><h3 id="mingling"><a class="header-anchor" href="#mingling">&gt;</a>mingling</h3><p>In the last few months I’ve been waving my hands in the dark around the question: “how can I be an effective activist? what do non-profits need from technologists?” After a morning welcome speech and warm coffee of happiness, there was a sort of non-profit club fair, where technologists got to ask questions and hear from organisers about their tech needs and the needs of the community.</p><p><img src="hack-the-ban.jpg" alt="hack the ban"></p><p>Some thoughts and observations:</p><ul><li>woah there’s no dedicated developer at a lot of these orgs. so it’s important that any tech setup (website, electronic donations page, email list) is very simple, readily safe/secure, and requires very little training</li><li>many orgs seem to feel a need for <em>something</em> (e.g. infographics, pamphlets, data visualisations) but can’t exactly articulate what it is. it is our job as technologists to extract their needs from listening to their goals, in a way that reminds me of being a tech consultant.</li><li>many things are done by hand (e.g. managing mailing lists). a no-background-knowledge-assumed kit/guide to automating these tasks could free up a lot of time/resources (but be careful of investment and maintenance time-cost)</li><li>with orgs that serve specific communities, <u>multilingual accessibility</u> is very important.</li></ul><h3 id="hacking"><a class="header-anchor" href="#hacking">&gt;</a>hacking</h3><p>Most of the participants came as individuals, and self-organised into groups that paired with the non-profits. I ended up among a wide range of experience and skillsets, and it was super cool watching everyone come together and the more senior folks take leadership, ask focused questions, and delegate. Thoughts from the hacking portion:</p><ul><li>project management and delegation is SO. IMPORTANT. good management is a productivity multiplier!</li><li>it’s great to be a generalist who can jump into things and figure out how existing stuff works</li><li>consultant skills are very useful – trying to decide tech stack, experience with working with different tools, pros/cons of various options</li><li>someone brought their graphics tablet, which was an excellent idea. I’m 100% throwing my wacom into my backpack next time for emergency wireframing/design prototyping</li><li>as with an ordinary hackathon, have project templates, communication channels, and staging environments ready to save precious time (but unlike an ordinary hackathon, it’s uncertain what existing systems we’d come across)</li></ul><p>I left feeling optimistic, with a reminder to be patient – it can be slow to find your footing within a space, be it industry or volunteering, because fundamentally it is about human relationships, which takes time. Slow is ok. I’m doing what I can.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/02/26/notes-from-a-civic-hackathon/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What am I reading? (January 2017)</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/02/14/What-am-I-reading-January-2017/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/02/14/What-am-I-reading-January-2017/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 01:21:08 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I love browsing other peoples’ reading lists!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
      </description>
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>I love browsing other peoples’ reading lists!</strong></p><a id="more"></a><p>My culture tells me that reading books is something a respectable intellectual should do a lot of, but it’s been pretty far down the list of priorities ever since I had to seriously come to terms with the fact that sustaining a regular sleep and exercise schedule is key to holding off crippling depression. Well now I’m on a nomadic sabatical and there is time for books again!</p><p>When I was back home over winter holiday, my brother was dragging his face through a book club book he hated, with the explanation that he found fulfillment in figuring out exactly what it was about a book that he hated. So I started a spreadsheet about my <em>feelings</em> of all the things I’ve been reading, because I too love dissecting my feelings and analysing my reactions to a precise degree yet still having very little command of my emotional muscles and tendons (a duality of theory/execution understood by anyone who has tried learning handstands or the butterfly stroke).</p><p>Here I’ll clean up and publish the monthly spreadsheet book reviews for your browsing pleasure!</p><!-- more --><h3 id="The-Fifth-Season-N-K-Jemisin"><a class="header-anchor" href="#The-Fifth-Season-N-K-Jemisin">&gt;</a>The Fifth Season - N.K Jemisin</h3><h4 id="fic-scific-10-10"><a class="header-anchor" href="#fic-scific-10-10">&gt;</a>fic, scific | 10/10</h4><p><em>The Fifth Season</em> is fucking fabulous, the best scifi/fantasy I’ve read in a really long time. The worldbuilding is stunning and thorough, depicting tribalism and societal manipulation in nuanced and real ways that is Too Real, you don’t get sat down with an explanation of anything that’s going on so there’s a lot of discovery (including the fact that the book is ACTUALLY SCIFI) through narrative, and every realisation feels intentional and well-placed. Queer/poly/trans representation is presented without cringe-worthy tokenness, and in fact is really good. Pacing is amazing and doesn’t let up. Graphic narrative that is so strong I had to read out of the corner of my eyes during particularly intense scenes. The way abusive emotional relationships (between family members, a racial group vs society, between mentor and student) are depicted are so tragic and multifaceted that you aren’t yelling at characters for doing the Wrong Thing, you’re angonising about how horrible and confusing being a person is. The writing does a bit of the high fantasy air to it (maybe that’s why I thought it was fantasy at first) that usually annoys me but I stopped being epsilon annoyed by it as soon as the story picked up. READ. THIS BOOK.</p><p>(also whenever I see a non-male author going by initials I get flashbacks of JK Rowling being advised that people wouldn’t read Harry Potter with a feminine name on the cover.)</p><h3 id="The-Obelisk-Gate-N-K-Jemisin"><a class="header-anchor" href="#The-Obelisk-Gate-N-K-Jemisin">&gt;</a>The Obelisk Gate - N.K Jemisin</h3><h4 id="fic-scific-read-this-if-you-liked-the-last-one"><a class="header-anchor" href="#fic-scific-read-this-if-you-liked-the-last-one">&gt;</a>fic, scific | read this if you liked the last one</h4><p>The second book in the series, continuing from before. It doesn’t win your heart with novelty like the first book, but it takes more steps into scifi and provides explanations and continues at breakneck pace. I liked it as a second book, and the third one is coming out later this year \o/</p><h3 id="Modern-Operating-Systems-Tanenbaum"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Modern-Operating-Systems-Tanenbaum">&gt;</a>Modern Operating Systems (Tanenbaum)</h3><h4 id="technical-computer-science-good-for-unrefined-systems-ragamuffins-me"><a class="header-anchor" href="#technical-computer-science-good-for-unrefined-systems-ragamuffins-me">&gt;</a>technical, computer science | good for unrefined systems ragamuffins (me)</h4><p>I’m reading along as my sister takes her major’s operating system’s course. This book gets personal with touches of snark and is what feels like a pretty approachable introduction to OS stuff. Weirdly enough it’s patching up the gaps of knowledge I have acquired through my backalley self-education on distributed systems as a bystander to the container wars last year.</p><h3 id="Limits-to-Growth"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Limits-to-Growth">&gt;</a>Limits to Growth</h3><h4 id="economy-systems-good-ideas-probs-not-worth-the-entire-read-for-most"><a class="header-anchor" href="#economy-systems-good-ideas-probs-not-worth-the-entire-read-for-most">&gt;</a>economy, systems | good ideas, probs not worth the entire read for most</h4><p>I am about 40% through this book. It seems to be a textbook used in some undergrad courses, about the world as systems and I noticed the terminology being similar to that of <em>Thinking in Systems</em> (which I also read 40% of, last year) – because Donella Meadows is an author on both books! It introduces a lot of interesting, abstract ideas on political and social sustainability with regards to growth, and the pitfalls of how politicians and voters think about growth and rates of growth. I got stuck at the part where the book goes into detail about water, land, and other resource consumption facts, which, while interesting and worthwhile, are probably more suited for a research project than my vague goal of trying to understand the big picture of why the world is going to shit. I’m planning to return to this book next month, skipping that section and getting through the rest of the ideas (maybe post my notes?)</p><h3 id="Training-for-the-New-Alpinism-Freedom-of-the-Hills"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Training-for-the-New-Alpinism-Freedom-of-the-Hills">&gt;</a>Training for the New Alpinism; Freedom of the Hills</h3><h4 id="Apparently-Freedom-of-the-Hills-is-the-Mountaineering-bible"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Apparently-Freedom-of-the-Hills-is-the-Mountaineering-bible">&gt;</a>Apparently Freedom of the Hills is the Mountaineering bible</h4><p>Mountaineering books that I started reading when I moved to the northeast and thought I would do a lot of mountaineering this season! That didn’t really happen for a variety of reasons, but that’s okay I’m going to be so prepared next year! Also I can’t believe no one told me how good Freedom of the Hills is as an introduction to technical mountaineering. Jeez. It’s just great. Super technical and with pictures!</p><h3 id="Ice-World"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Ice-World">&gt;</a>Ice World</h3><h4 id="technical-ice-climbing-it’s-like-a-story-and-also-a-manual"><a class="header-anchor" href="#technical-ice-climbing-it’s-like-a-story-and-also-a-manual">&gt;</a>technical, ice climbing | it’s like a story and also a manual</h4><p>This is an older technical ice climbing book that I started to read from my gym’s little climbing library when I thought I would do ice climbing this season :P Same story as above. I like how it starts with a bunch of stories, and has a friendly narrative-approach to teaching, including a section where the author instructs the finer points of glacier traversal by documenting the process of <em>teaching his wife through a hands-on expedition</em>.</p><h3 id="On-The-Road-Jack-Kerouac"><a class="header-anchor" href="#On-The-Road-Jack-Kerouac">&gt;</a>On The Road - Jack Kerouac</h3><h4 id="semi-autobiographical-travel-counterculture-DNF"><a class="header-anchor" href="#semi-autobiographical-travel-counterculture-DNF">&gt;</a>semi-autobiographical, travel, counterculture | DNF</h4><p>I didn’t finish this book. I couldn’t get into Jack Kerouac’s prose or the story. Which is super sad, because I’m a iconoclast hippie dirtbag like Kerouac and I keep seeing good quotes from his writing and praise for this work and I really wanted to like it! At first pass it should have everything I like a lot: stories from the road, weird hitchhiking stuff, the windy, uncommited flow of consciousness style that I love in Didion and post-modernists like DFW. I really disliked the people the protag surrounds himself with and feel frustrated that I have to spend time with these characters, who feel kind of worthless and kind of like the type of trash I have long cut out of my own life, sexist attitudes and dishonesty and fuck-all laziness and apathy and self-pitiful ennui. I just don’t need to wade through the maturity level of the social landscape of this time in the author’s life I guess.</p><h3 id="The-Golden-Compass-Philip-Pullman"><a class="header-anchor" href="#The-Golden-Compass-Philip-Pullman">&gt;</a>The Golden Compass - Philip Pullman</h3><h4 id="YA-fic-childhood-reread-exceeds-expectations-recollection"><a class="header-anchor" href="#YA-fic-childhood-reread-exceeds-expectations-recollection">&gt;</a>YA fic, childhood reread | exceeds expectations/recollection</h4><p>The subject of childhood rereads came up when I was hanging out with elementary/middle school friends over winter holiday, and I picked The Golden Compass to revist.</p><p>HOW is this a children’s novel?? The protag being a prepubescent child is the only thing children about this book. It deals with loads of mature themes (balance of power between church/state, love between a semi-immortal and humans), geography and culture comes at you really fast and without much explanation, plays on alt-history with renamings of abstract concepts (science is called philosophy or theology, electricity is called anbaric) that are hard to catch without an early high school education and without understanding of which it would seem a lot of the magic and meaning in the story might be lost?? I certainly don’t remember catching ANY of this in my first readthrough (in middle school). In fact I have retained almost nothing from the first readthrough except that there were daemons and armoured bears, probably because it all went completely over my head but I liked bears and wanted a daemon. It 1000% feels like a young adult book written for adults. Even more so than stuff like The Hunger Games, which doesn’t feel nearly as nuanced! Hunger Games feels so straightforward and civil compared to this world, jesus.</p><p>My one gripe is that, once I step back a little from the action and world-building, the plot appears very deus ex machina. Pretty much all conflict is overcome by a third party that miraculously swoops in with exactly the correct skillset to perfectly conduct a rescue. This is forgivable, given that it IS a children’s novel so it’s supposed to read like a story/tale rather than realistic rendition of how the world works, and that the action and characters are really exciting and distract from the plot drop-ins. Also the characters really pop and are super fun. Great book, great re-read, the opposite of disappointment!</p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2017/02/14/What-am-I-reading-January-2017/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>signaling in tech is some fucked up shit</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2016/11/30/Signaling-in-tech-is-some-fucked-up-shit/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2016/11/30/Signaling-in-tech-is-some-fucked-up-shit/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 08:07:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am exactly as cool as I was before I started writing clojure.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
      </description>
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>I am exactly as cool as I was before I started writing clojure.</strong></p><a id="more"></a><p>I’ve had a short, short life as a programmer and I’ve spent a lot of it making websites. Back in the day (as in a couple years ago) when I told other software people I’m a web developer, I got treated like shit. I was a lower class of coder because I wasn’t “solving cool problems” because making web sites is easy. It was sad and confusing to receive unjustified hatred but I loved the internet and I thought it’s pretty neat to make things that everyone can use and I like the visual component to my projects so I’d just go secretly cry in the bathroom (cool tricked I learned in college) like an ordinary functioning adult.</p><p>Somewhere along the way there was a massive rebranding so then I was doing literally the same things but now I’m a Frontend Engineer or UI Engineer. Occasionally I’d still get trashed by other coders but that’s ok, I even get to sit with the other software folks sometimes!</p><p>I found web and design communities where people do good web things and encourage each other to be better. It’s cool. Love is out there.</p><p>A month or two ago I started picking up clojure. I don’t know why other people learn new programming languages, but I didn’t know anything about clojure’s rich history and I wasn’t chasing the Beauty of Lisp or the superior mindset it would teach me or hoping to harness the performance or flexibility. I had no fucking clue about any of that. I’d just started reading <a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/sicp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SICP</a> because I missed computer science after bumping around in industryland, and it seemed trivial to swap scheme for clojure while doing the exercises in the book and end up being competent at a language I heard rumours that people use sometimes rather than a language I knew people used never.</p><p>And I liked it! It was my first lisp and yeah coming from javascript and python I liked the quaint syntax, and the way everything is all about these couple of data structures, and thinking functionally and non-mutably (word salad word salad). More significantly, I’d just left my previous job pretty much hating programming, and clojure was reminding me about why I like programming, and that was lovely. I noticed it was possible to use clojure to make UIs via clojurescript and figured it’d be a cool way to connect these two interests and go full circle.</p><p>I mentioned to some people I was learning clojure. Everyone was <em>super</em> into this. People started telling me I was really cool. I noticed people making all these wildly positive assumptions about my programming ability despite not having read a single line of code I’ve written ever. I instantly get elevated to a respect-worthy status for free and maybe for people who are used to being treated well that’s not a big deal, but coming from being treated like trash after telling people I am a web person the contrast was super intense and really obvious. I felt like I stumbled into a mystery bizarro-verse where you get dignity by default. It was SO WEIRD.</p><p>It’s fucked up that being interested in this random programming language, not even for the reasons the fangirls love it, suddenly caused everyone to start being nice to me when I’m in fact the same trash can that I’ve been all along. Coming upon the Correct Signal by accident made it all feel extra wrong and extra strange, like I killed a man and wore his skin for a suit and suddenly inherited all the achievements ever made in that body.</p><p>I know railing against signaling is itself a signal that I am a naive member of society who has yet to smash out of my youthful optimism chrysalis into the apathetic reality machine. Signaling is going to be there no matter what, because human nature. All I can do is reflect in stupid amazement at this experience and compel you to treat others with respect by default. Seriously.</p><p>–<br><span class="mute"><em>EPILOGUE 2018/07/29 15:11PST</em></span></p><p><span class="mute">Wowow HI HACKER NEWS \o/ my meatspace self (ordinarily in mountains on sundays) is having an unusually urban weekend at the <a href="https://explorabl.es/jam" target="_blank" rel="noopener">explorables jam</a> when suddenly I start getting an influx of emails from (shockingly kind) randos.</span></p><p><span class="mute">I admit I am slightly terrified to wade into internet comments so I write to you here:</span></p><p><span class="mute">I had published this post out of bitterness shortly after I had decided to hard bail from San Francisco and live out of a bright orange backpack in various places doing various small projects and drifting in and out of small communities. I felt so adrift and disenchanted, if you know me then you know I have a huge amount of energy and at the time nowhere to put it to.</span></p><p><span class="mute">Right now I find myself back in California, but under a completely different set of circumstances and attitudes: I am doing work that I feel is meaningful on a supportive and gentle team, I live in a wonderful house of interesting and rad roommates, I see my family often, and yes I feel the ambient pressure of a young american professional, yes sometimes it is rough and I lose sight of what is good, but overall I am satisfied with my life trajectory and have found my niche in the world. It makes me so sad that my most relatable content is the things I have posted out of bitterness two years ago from a past life that I no longer empathise or identify with. But perhaps it will comfort you to know that things can get better! that there are wonderful communities out there, perhaps difficult to find, but they exist. Find these people, surround yourself with them, and lift others up with you when you have the bandwidth. I know that happily ever after epilogues ruin the story but this is a story arc that I want to trash because sometimes when you are in the depths of cynicism it feeds on itself and it is helpful to remember that things are getting better all the time, whatever you are in you can pull yourself out and one day you too can be jammin with fun weirdos into the sunset \o/</span></p><p><span class="mute">(if you want to interact with me your best bet is twitter @<a href="https://twitter.com/daiyitastic" target="_blank" rel="noopener">daiyitastic</a> or email. please be kind.)</span></p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2016/11/30/Signaling-in-tech-is-some-fucked-up-shit/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A week on the Swiss Via Alpina</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2016/11/08/A-week-on-the-Swiss-Via-Alpina/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2016/11/08/A-week-on-the-Swiss-Via-Alpina/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;img src=&quot;/blog/2016/11/08/A-week-on-the-Swiss-Via-Alpina/daiyi-hikin.jpg&quot; class=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;daiyi unable to face the camera due to overwhelming beauty of alps&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a week walking the Via Alpina trail in Switzerland from late September to early October 2016.
      
      </description>
      
      <enclosure url="http://daiyi.co/blog/daiyi-hikin.jpg" type="image" />
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="/blog/2016/11/08/A-week-on-the-Swiss-Via-Alpina/daiyi-hikin.jpg" class="" title="daiyi unable to face the camera due to overwhelming beauty of alps"><p>I spent a week walking the Via Alpina trail in Switzerland from late September to early October 2016.<a id="more"></a> I inevitably collect cool thoughts and cool photos when I hike for 8 hours a day and have always wanted to write a trip report, but motivation/time is eaten when I rejoin society and work/school. I have neither of those responsibilities right now! Posts will be serialised under <a href="/blog/tags/via-alpina">Via Alpina</a>.</p><h3 id="when-you-go-to-a-fancy-modern-country-to-sleep-on-the-side-of-the-road"><a class="header-anchor" href="#when-you-go-to-a-fancy-modern-country-to-sleep-on-the-side-of-the-road">&gt;</a>when you go to a fancy modern country to sleep on the side of the road</h3><p>I love that the alps are super accessible (grandmas and dogs and babies all over the places, rails running out of every town to the top of every pass), and people go there specifically to enjoy the European charm and convenience of mountain cabins/huts. So of course I ignored all the modern comforts the country had to offer, wild camping and hitchhiking instead. I took one train, two hours from Zurich to my arbitrarily selected trailhead in Engelberg, which was a fresh and smooth experience that, like all the other Swiss things, put the quality of their counterparts in other countries to shame, but also used all my food budget for the month. It was lovely for being the only train I pay for my entire stay in Europe.</p><p>The trail was really developed and full of cows and people, so we got pretty creative about finding places to sleep! (Ominous foreshadowing music)</p><h3 id="Contradictions"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Contradictions">&gt;</a>Contradictions</h3><ul><li>I’m on a fairly tight budget, but Switzerland is notoriously expensive.</li><li>I like packing ultralight but I was flying to a wedding right and needed nice clothes ✨</li></ul><p>Even with cautionary tales of $20 McD from friends who visited earlier in the summer, I was unable to handle how crazy Switzerland prices were, even with my recent past life in the luxurious San Francisco tech startup reality sphere. We brought our food in from Germany, an excellent country with reasonable grocery bills and an appreciation for tasty dehydrated meals (in the US you have to go to a sport store for that).</p><h3 id="Here-are-some-ways-I-prepared-for-the-trip-because-I-sometimes-get-questions-about-how-I-travel-o"><a class="header-anchor" href="#Here-are-some-ways-I-prepared-for-the-trip-because-I-sometimes-get-questions-about-how-I-travel-o">&gt;</a>Here are some ways I prepared for the trip, because I sometimes get questions about how I travel \o/</h3><p>Basically I like to collect a ton of info so I can put off deciding on specifics for as long as possible. This is the kind of thinking that both leads me to sleeping on the side of the road but also in a secluded magical fairy wonderland (both happened).</p><ul><li><a href="https://activityworkshop.net/hiking/alpinepassroute" target="_blank" rel="noopener">activity workshop .net</a>, an oddly-named website which provided kickass gps maps and elevation reliefs and info about the towns along the Swiss via alpina.</li><li><a href="http://osmand.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OSM-AND</a> and <a href="http://maps.me/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Maps.me</a> android apps, which I used to read gps coordinates/trails from above. Both superior to google maps for (my style of) travel because of<ul><li>excellent offline support</li><li>easy bookmarking/note-taking that exports to standard formats</li><li>you can search for bathrooms omg</li><li>more data for hiking trail/natural features (eg mountain peaks)</li></ul></li></ul><ul><li>I also highly recommend the <a href="http://osmand.net/features?id=contour-lines-plugin" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OSM-AND topo plugin</a> for a super awesome hiking experience :D</li><li><a href="http://hitchwiki.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hitchwiki</a> – a wiki and map contributed by hitchhikers for hitchhikers!</li><li><a href="https://getpocket.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pocket</a>, which I used to offline cache aforementioned resources.</li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2016/11/08/A-week-on-the-Swiss-Via-Alpina/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I went to IndieWebCamp</title>
      <link>http://daiyi.co/blog/2016/11/08/I-went-to-IndieWebCamp/</link>
      <guid>http://daiyi.co/blog/2016/11/08/I-went-to-IndieWebCamp/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 06:30:04 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;or, justification for satisfying annual urge to completely revamp web presence.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am inspired by the promises of an &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/why&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Indie Web&lt;/a&gt;. Owning your data, cool. A single source of truth to your content and identity, nice. Possibility of sinking countless hours into configuring your own corner of the internet, ok you got me there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m hearing some rattling in my internet social spheres about how content silos are making the internet more homogeneous, forcing you to conform and contort your thoughts into prescribed formatting, that force of nature that causes experts in their fields to blast out 50-part tweetstorms that should be written in an article instead. Hey you sound exactly like the indiewebcamp people!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;check it out&lt;/a&gt;. They’re nice, too (:&lt;/p&gt;
      
      </description>
      
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>or, justification for satisfying annual urge to completely revamp web presence.</strong></p><p>I am inspired by the promises of an <a href="https://indieweb.org/why" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Indie Web</a>. Owning your data, cool. A single source of truth to your content and identity, nice. Possibility of sinking countless hours into configuring your own corner of the internet, ok you got me there.</p><p>I’m hearing some rattling in my internet social spheres about how content silos are making the internet more homogeneous, forcing you to conform and contort your thoughts into prescribed formatting, that force of nature that causes experts in their fields to blast out 50-part tweetstorms that should be written in an article instead. Hey you sound exactly like the indiewebcamp people!</p><p>Go <a href="https://indieweb.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">check it out</a>. They’re nice, too (:</p><a id="more"></a><h3 id="personal-minutia"><a class="header-anchor" href="#personal-minutia">&gt;</a>personal minutia</h3><p>This is going to be a static site because it is just a blog; if I am generating enough content to need a database behind it I should probably be getting paid for it. Fun fact: in middle school, my diary was a series of .txt files.</p><p>I know everyone and github is really into jekyll, but I decided to use <a href="https://hexo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hexo</a> to generate my static site for the following reasons:</p><ul><li>I’m a node developer (bring on the hate) who is too lazy to install ruby stuff on my computer.</li><li>hexo’s developer community is surprisingly full of chinese people. I am forced to face my illiteracy and read a lot of chinese. It will be good practice :D</li></ul><p>Speaking of which, I’m pretty surprised I don’t encounter a lot more chinese developers on the internet, seeing as how there’s a lot of cool people and technology in china. It seems the Great Firewall runs deep.</p><p>Cool, hopefully you can see some longform appear here in the near future! Or this will devolve back into a nature photoblog (I’ll keep that going on my <a href="http://tumblr.com/daiyi" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tumblr</a>). Either way.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://daiyi.co/blog/2016/11/08/I-went-to-IndieWebCamp/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
